<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="MagicalCreatures.xsl"?>  -->
<!--
	<title>Creatures Type List Database</title>
	<description>Creatures list was converted from Terminal Groupings *.TG to XML on 01/18/11. The list was updated to reflect external use by Exploring The Bleak: Online on 11-12-12. The list is also used in Plains of Sedia : Origins, Developed by Nathaniel Inman of The Other Experiment Studio found @ www.theoestudio.com. All contents within are licensed under GPLv3
-->
<itemlist>
	<item number="1">
		<name>Abada</name>
		<weight>175</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>a</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="5">unique</tileset>
		<description>Remarkably similar to the Unicorn except they bear on their heads two crooked horns instead of one straight horn. They are also thought to be the size of a small donkey, have a dark bay color and have a boar's tail. Like the unicorn, its horns are thought to act as an antidote to poisons. It reportedly lives in The Tropics of Dumet and is the lesser known variety of its cousin the Unicorn.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="2">
		<name>Abaddon</name>
		<weight>340</weight>
		<height>120</height>
		<symbol>A</symbol>
		<hitpoints>18</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d12</damage>
		<tileset x="7" y="7">unique</tileset>
		<description>Abaddon literally translates from Narsik into destruction, ruin, and perdition. This name is also used to refer to the palace of Dekkashraen. Abaddon is described as the king of a group of locust-like creatures with the faces of men, the hair of women, tails of scorpions, teeth of lions, and wings that sound like the thunder of horses' hooves charging into battle. He is the chief of the demons of the seventh heirarchy. Though there may be more than one Abaddon, they are only talked about in myths and there are no accounts of them being seen, though it's rumored they hail from deep within The Bleak.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="3">
		<name>Adar Llwch Gwin</name>
		<weight>250</weight>
		<height>67</height>
		<symbol>l</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="1">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Huge magical birds that can understand human speech and obey ALL commands given to them by their master. An Adar Llwch Gwin looks similar to a griffin. An Adar generally sticks to where it was born so they haven't moved far from the Amari Hinterlands, though some have been rumored to roam Lythantos' Shrine. </description>
	</item>
	<item number="4">
		<name>Adlet</name>
		<weight>90</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>d</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="11">monster4</tileset>
		<description>A bloodthirsty, cannibalistic race of canine like hominids said to be the offspring of an Karthaginian womans unnatural mating with a ferocious giant red dog. Adlets roam the Frozen Wastes as scavengers. An Adlet can weigh from 60 stones to 190 stones depending on whether it has eated recently. Adlets stand 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="5">
		<name>Addonexus</name>
		<weight>270</weight>
   		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>D</symbol>
		<hitpoints>13</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="12">monster3</tileset>
		<description>An Addonexus is a large white canine. They use pure energy which causes them to be able to control the elements and heal physical wounds. They age approximately 3 years slower than normal humans however, and are only capable of living 75 years at the most. Addonexus were born during The War of Souls. It's said they will die the day the Everspark is put back together as the wandering energy of the Everpsark is said to encompass their souls. Addonexus have been spotted all throughout Sedia though they are normally seen within caves or among Adlets with whom they become packleaders. An Addonexus is generally 2 to 270 stones in weight and needs little sustenance to live efficiently. An addonexus generally stands 50 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="6">
		<name>Afanc</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>20</height>
		<symbol>f</symbol>
		<hitpoints>5</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="10">monster3</tileset>
		<description>An Afanc is a creature from Elven folklore that lives in lakes. It's description differs highly, ranging from dwarf, beaver, crocodile, and is sometimes said to be a demon, but it is most favourably depicted as a large frog with claws on all limbs. The Afanc is sometimes said to have magical powers and even the ability to speak draconian. In one tale it uses these powers to turn its thrashing of the lake into the mythical deluge that appears in many mythologies. Afanc have been rumored to reign from within the moran wetlands as well as Fae Lake within Mellowdeep Marsh. An Afanc weighs 30 stones and stands 20 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="7">
		<name>Agloolik</name>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>g</symbol>
		<hitpoints>7</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="10">monster3</tileset>
		<description>A good spirit of the Doonan Elk. A benevolent spirit in Doonan mythology, it lived under the ice and helped hunters and fishermen. Agloolik lives about the Frozen Waste and because it is a spirit doesn't weigh anything. It's rumored the Agloolik would stand the height of a man if upright, but is always depicted sitting down within water, curled up in a ball.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="8">
		<name>Agta</name>
		<weight>210</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>G</symbol>
		<hitpoints>14</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="5">monster3</tileset>
		<description>An Agta is a tree demon but with more human characteristics. It is described as being in between 70 to 90 stones tall, brown, and a hairy male with a beard. Agta are normally described as smoking a big tobacco pipe, whose strong smell would attract human attention. The Agta is supposed to hold a magical white stone, a little smaller in size than a quail egg. Should any person happen to obtain this stone, the Agta could grant wishes. Agta are not necessarily considered to be evil. Agta may make contact with people to offer friendship, or if it is attracted to a woman. If a Agta befriends any human, especially because of love, the Agta will consistently follow its "love interest" throughout life. Agta are also said to play pranks on people, frequently making travelers become disoriented and lose their way in the mountains or in the woods. Agta hail within all woodland areas and are often mistaken for Dryads. Agta are generally 210 stones in weight.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="9">
		<name>Alerion</name>
		<weight>40</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>r</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="6" y="1">monster5</tileset>
		<description>An alerion lives near humid dry places. Alerions are large eagle-like birds who have children only once every 60 years. Alerions have a wide wing span and are rarely seen as they fly very high in the sky and land but once each day. Alerion stands approximately 30 stones tall and weighs but 30-40 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="10">
		<name>Ahuizhotl</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>z</symbol>
		<hitpoints>18</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d10</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="10">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Meaning 'water oppossum', also called Sun Dog, the Ahuizotl is a vicious, savage predator. It resembles a medium-sized dog with a monkey's paws and a human hand at the end of its tail. The creature has also been described as otter-like creature with five hands, one on it's tail, capable of manipulation. The Ahuizotl was a feared creature supposed to live in or near water. It drags people and fishermen under the water using the hand on his tail. Its said to only eat travelers eyes, teeth, and nails. Ahuizhotl stand approximately 30 stones tall and weigh 60-110 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="11">
		<name>Akki</name>
		<weight>230</weight>
		<height>130</height>
		<symbol>k</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="7">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Hideous, gigantic, creatures with sharp claws, wild hair, and two long horns growing from their heads, Akki are fierce. They are humanoid for the most part, but occasionally they are shown with unnatural features such as odd numbers of eyes or extra fingers and toes. Their skin may be any number of colours, but red and blue are particularly common. Akki is often depicted as glutinous, lustful, and ill-tempered though easily distracted by crude humour. Akki are 130 Stones tall and weigh 230-280 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="12">
		<name>Alphyn</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>p</symbol>
		<hitpoints>19</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="8">unique</tileset>
		<description>Alphyn is a wonderful wolf creature featured in heraldry. Alphyn sports a dragon's scaly underbelly and forelimbs, a long knotted tail, large pointed ears, and a thin, pointed tongue. Alphyns are not winged and cannot fly, but it's said that they might be able to breath fire much like a dragon. Alphyn are 80-120 stones, and stand 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="13">
		<name>Amphisbaena</name>
		<weight>15</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>P</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="0">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Amphisbaena are said to be winged snakes with a main head, and secondary head on it's tail. Amphisbaena feed on the rotting dead and most generally inhabit crypts or old ruins. Amphisbaena prefer very hot climates that resemble barrens or deserts - though it cannot stray too far from the dead corpses as it's required to feed often. Amphisbaena weigh approximately 15 stones and span 30 to 60 stones in length.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="14">
		<name>Amphithere</name>
		<weight>100</weight>
		<height>70</height>
		<symbol>m</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="3">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Amphitheres are passive beasts with a serpentine body and feathered wings. They kill by strangulation with their tales or burning with their breath. Amphithere's gaze is said to be hypnotic, so observers must avert their gaze from their eyes. They inspire fear in those who see them, but are in fact, rather poor fighters. Amphitheres stand 70 stones tall and weigh approximately 100 to 120 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="15">
		<name>Ankou</name>
		<weight>180</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>K</symbol>
		<hitpoints>9</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="9" y="3">unique</tileset>
		<description>Ankous are seen as a death omen, and are said to collect the souls of the dead. They appear taller than they are, usually 80 stones tall, and are haggard figures with long white hair and a revolting head that can see everything in each direction. Upon arrival to collect a soul the Ankou is said to make a mounful wail much like the sound of a banshee. Ankous weigh around 180 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="16">
		<name>Aspis</name>
		<weight>250</weight>
		<height>90</height>
		<symbol>s</symbol>
		<hitpoints>17</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="6" y="1">dragon</tileset>
		<description>A winged drake, said to have carried a carbuncle stone on its head. Aspis are incredibly gentle drakes that live on the sides of southern cliffs and feed on the birds and gulls that fly the beaches nearby. Aspis' are long-lived creatures who live in small packs of families. They are sometimes timid and don't fare well to being coerced. They have long claws at the end of their wings they use during battle and a long mandible much like a teradactyl. Aspis weigh 200 to 300 stones and stand 80 to 90 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="17">
		<name>Asrai</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>S</symbol>
		<hitpoints>11</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="9">monster2</tileset>
		<description>Asrai are very beautiful and appear to never age, living usually up to a hundred years old. Asrai are aquatic faries that can appear to have webbed feet or hands. If sunlight touches them, they are said to die and turn into a puddle of water. Asrai are 30 stones in weight, and 50 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="18">
		<name>Aswang</name>
    	<weight>30</weight>
     	<height>30</height>
    	<symbol>w</symbol>
    	<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
    	<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="6">unique</tileset>
		<description>Aswang are ghouls that feed on young children or unborn babies. They appear as regular townsmen by day and prefer an occupation related to meat such as butchery. During the night they transform from human into an animal. Aswang can diguise themselves as pigs, dogs, or black birds. Supposedly if a person looks at them in the eyes, the reflection should appear inverted. During their nocturnal activies, they walk with their feet facing backwards and toenails reversed.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="19">
		<name>Bai Ze</name>
		<weight>40</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>i</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="6" y="6">unique</tileset>
		<description>Bai Ze were worshipped as guardian spirits for herbal medicine in the old age, before the war of souls. They look much like large white lions and can have extra eyes on their face or back. Bai Ze are usually considered to be quite intelligent and well-read creatures. Bai Ze are mostly now hid in seclusion within the Bleak as they have grown frail over thousands of years. Bai Ze weigh merely 30-50 stones and stone 60 stones tall. They are not guardian spirits, but merely sub-earth elementals.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="20">
		<name>Balam</name>
		<weight>180</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>b</symbol>
		<hitpoints>15</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="7">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Balam are supernatural jaguars that guard nature and protect villagers of certain distinguishable areas found sacred. Balam are only whispered legend - possibly as those who have seen them haven't survived. Balam were told to be 30 stones tall and weigh 180 stones. Such areas they might protect might be within the Forest of Frost or within the Old Kingdom.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="21">
		<name>Balrog</name>
		<weight>3500</weight>
		<height>175</height>
		<symbol>B</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="7">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Balrogs are tall and thick giants with the ability to shroud themselves within fire or darkness. They prefer to use whips as their weapon of choice and are slavedrivers to Narsinian frontline war-ranks against Mandak's Legion. It's said that only dragons or even wyrms equal their ferocity and danger. Balrogs inhabit a clear 3000 to 4000 stones of weight and stand 150 to 180 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="22">
		<name>Banshee</name>
		<weight>170</weight>
		<height>55</height>
		<symbol>e</symbol>
		<hitpoints>15</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="6">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Banshees are rarely seen but it's told they are omens of death, a warning to certain families that their time has come. Her mourning call is often given at night when someone is about to die. Banshees are said to resemble bats and humans alike weighing approximately 170 stones and standing 50 to 60 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="23">
		<name>Barbegazi</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>R</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="4">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Barbegazis are a type of gnome that can be found at the tops of frozen mountains. They are rarely seen, these creatures enjoy helping each other and set subtle warnings of trespassers. It's common to see Barbegazi form as groups against trespassers to more quickly dispatch an emey that they find formidable. Barbegazi's are the height of quicklings and weigh no more than 30 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="24">
		<name>Barghest</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>h</symbol>
		<hitpoints>14</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="12">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Barghest are dangerous black dogs with huge teeth and claws. The name barghest was attributed from ghosts or bear spirits as it was often said a barghest helped transport the souls of mad men to the heart of Kyros where Dekkashraen refactures the souls into the shape of a new barghest: Dangerous, swift, and feared. A barghest directly resembles a large wolf in weight and height, 80 stones, and 20 to 30 stones respectfully.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="25">
		<name>Basilisk</name>
		<weight>330</weight>
		<height>120</height>
		<symbol>L</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="1">monster7</tileset>
		<description>Basilisks are said to have the power to cause death by simply peering into it's foes eyes. It has the tail of a snake, the head of a rooster, and small wings that it can't use to fly. Basilisks have thick, resilient scales that protects their bodies from attack - predominately from their ancient predator, the Crok. Basilisks weigh 252 to 330 stones and span 120 stones in length.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="26">
		<name>Bastet</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>20</height>
		<symbol>t</symbol>
		<hitpoints>12</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="9" y="5">unique</tileset>
		<description>Bastet are warecats or halfhuman, halfcat. Bastet hide in the wild and are rebuked by humans and elves as deformities of nature. Bastets are angry beings who have rarely been seen showing sympathy to travelers, and similarly kill each other like animals fighting for territory. It is surprising that they still exist today given their shortage of brood and seldom breeding. Bastet weigh approximately 80 stones and stand 20 to 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="27">
		<name>Baykok</name>
		<weight>50</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>y</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="1">undead</tileset>
		<description>Baykoks are walking skeletons but with a thin translucent skin and fearsome red eyes glowing from sockets within their skull. Baykoks prey on warriors and prefers clubs or ethereal bow and arrows. Baykok aren't necessarily considered skeletal as they are controled by living organisms. They are a complex being that weighs no more than 50 stones and stand 50 to 60 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="28">
		<name>Black Annis</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>N</symbol>
		<hitpoints>18</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="6" y="0">undead</tileset>
		<description>Black annis were once thought to be a boogyman story told to ornery children to scare good into them. Black annis are very real and live mostly in the swamps and marshes of Sedia as dark crones with iron claws for hands by which they use to hunt small children. They prefer humans but will settle for halflings or the occasional elf child. Black annis resemble the weight and height of a standard human.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="29">
		<name>Blurr</name>
		<weight>150</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>u</symbol>
		<hitpoints>5</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="3">undead</tileset>
		<description>Blurrs are vague human-like figures that are often seen randomly near sides of trees. They emit a frequency of sound that interferes with sentient creatures perception and makes beings forget or not notice blurrs are there. Though hard to notice, these creatures are incredibly deadly beings that emplore intense magical energies and skills used before the fall of the Old Kingdom. Blurrs are 150-180 stones in weight, and 60 to 70 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="30">
		<name>Bunyip</name>
		<weight>50</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>Y</symbol>
		<hitpoints>5</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="2">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Bunyips tend to lurk in swamps, billabongs, creeks, riverbeds or waterholes. Bunyips are considered water spirits and tend to resemble fish with legs with body characteristics of a squid and suckers on the palms of it's feet. They are roughly the size of a dog and weigh no more than 50 stones. Bunyips prey on weakened or disabled small creatures and are otherwise incredibly passive.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="31">
		<name>Caladrius</name>
		<weight>8</weight>
		<height>3</height>
		<symbol>c</symbol>
		<hitpoints>10</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="7">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Caladrius are said to be snow-white birds who can tell when someone is on the verge of death. They are said to swoop down and emerse the target with magical curing energies, feeding on the sickness only. They are thought as wings of Ettphemone and are highly sought after, sometimes sold for truckloads of Sovern to kings or queens. Caladrius weigh no more than 2 to 3 stones and stand 5 to 8 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="32">
		<name>Calygreyhound</name>
		<weight>120</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>C</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="1">monster5</tileset>
		<description>The calygreyhound is most commonly shown with teh head of a wildcat, body of a deer, forelegs of an eagle, and hinde legs of an ox. Calygreyhounds are fast and passive creatures that are seen in the Southeastern location of the Old Kingdom. Calygreyhounds are 80 to 120 stones and stand 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="33">
		<name>Campacti</name>
		<weight>400</weight>
		<height>200</height>
		<symbol>M</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d12</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="4">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Compacti are daemons, vast dragons whose bodies were slain to release earth and sinew. Campacti inhabit the deeps of the water and look most similarly to crocodiles. Campacti are 300 to 400 stones and range from 120 to 200 stones in height and width.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="34">
		<name>Canaima</name>
		<weight>300</weight>
		<height>200</height>
		<symbol>I</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="3">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Canaima was a pagan god that was said to have the ability to change form or shape into whatever he possessed. In actuality Canaima are shapeshifting creatures that prefer to disguise themselves as humans unless the need to flee takes course and they shift as is necessary to perform actions. Canaimas weight depend on their form, as does their height. They are rarely found anywhere but within the wilds of forests.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="35">
		<name>Catoblepas</name>
		<weight>600</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>o</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="7" y="7">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Catoblepas are said to have the body of a buffalo and the head of a hog. The back is composed of scales that protect the creature, and it's head due to it's weight is always pointed downward. It's said that it's stare instills fear into it's enemies. Catoblepas are passive-aggresive creatures that tend to prefer plants and grass for food but will kill other animals to play with their corpse. A Catoblepas weighs about 300 to 600 stones and stands 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="36">
		<name>Centaur</name>
		<weight>275</weight>
		<height>70</height>
		<symbol>E</symbol>
		<hitpoints>18</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="5">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Centaurs are creatures that have the head, torso, and arms of  a man while having the body and legs of a horse. Centaurs are said to be extremely heavy drinkers. They carry bows and are very short tempered creatures. Centaurs weigh 224 to 275 stones and stand generally at 70 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="37">
		<name>Cerastes</name>
		<weight>70</weight>
		<height>70</height>
		<symbol>T</symbol>
		<hitpoints>18</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="4">monster4</tileset>
		<description>A Cerastes is a serpent-like imp with four small pairs of horns that resemble a ram. A cerastes hides within sand of deserts with it's horns protruding to deceive animals into think it's food. A Cerastes stands no more than 30 stones tall and weighs 50 to 70 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="38">
		<name>Cerberus</name>
		<weight>800</weight>
		<height>120</height>
		<symbol>W</symbol>
		<hitpoints>12</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="5">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Cerberus is most commonly depicted as a giant dog with three heads, and sometimes a mane composed of snakes or tails of a serpent. The cerberus is regarded as a great and fearsome creature and emplores much strength. Cerberus is found only within the Bleak and is said to range from 250 to 800 stones and stand 80 to 120 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="39">
		<name>Charybdis</name>
		<weight>1800</weight>
		<height>800</height>
		<symbol>Ç</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d12</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="2">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Charybdis is a creature that sits under the water and causes whirlpools by opening her gaping mouth and sucking in and swallowing everything, including ships and sea animals. When she exhales, she spits everything out. It is unknown what this colossal creature looks like.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="40">
		<name>Chimaera</name>
		<weight>450</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>ç</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="9">monster2</tileset>
		<description>Chimaera's are part lion, goat, and snake. Chimaera's are the second most popular beast to guard portals, next to dragons. They are all females and mate solely with dragons. With the decline of dragons came the decline of Chimaeras. A chimaera stands 80 stones tall and weighes roughly 450 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="41">
		<name>Cinnamologus</name>
		<weight>180</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>O</symbol>
		<hitpoints>2</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="8" y="5">unique</tileset>
		<description>A Cinnamologus is a giant bird who is said to collect and nest among cinnamon trees. This cinnamon bird is incredbly passive and cares only to eat the leaves of it's tree whilst planting more and protecting it's young. The only time a Cinnamologus will fight if it's cornered or protecting young. A Cinnamologus resembles a phoenix with the aura of ice instead of fire and does not rise from ashes, but instead lives centuries. Cinnamologus is just shy of a Rocs size and sizes may vary depending on the availability of cinnamon trees and the age of the bird.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="42">
		<name>Clurichaun</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>U</symbol>
		<hitpoints>1</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="0">unique</tileset>
		<description>Clurichuans are mischievous imps who have drinking problems. They dwell mostly within Narsis and have hobbies that consist of thievary or murder, by which they do without any honor whatsoever, killing enemies during their sleep. Clurichuans aren't incredibly strong and are considered creatures due to their incredibly low intelligence and inability to communicate. Clurichuans stand 20-30 stones and weigh between 20 and 80 stones depending on the availability of liquor and food.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="43">
		<name>Cyclops</name>
		<weight>700</weight>
		<height>150</height>
		<symbol>ÿ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>4</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="8" y="2">unique</tileset>
		<description>Cyclops are members of a primordial race. Cyclopes are giants with a single eye in the middle of their forehead and a foul disposition. The first cyclopes were smiths who worked underground. It's said that dwarves are the result of cyclops preference to underground work, growing small in size to fit their preferred setting. Cyclops are 600 to 700 stones and stand 120 to 150 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="44">
		<name>Dip</name>
		<weight>150</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>ï</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="8">unique</tileset>
		<description>With a resemblance to death dogs, a dip is said to be an evil, black, hairy dog that is an emissary of Dekkashraen. It's said Dips suck peoples blood for sustenance and play with their dead bodies, leaving them about it's lair to ward off intruders. Dips are 50 to 150 stones and stand 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="45">
		<name>Dobhar-chu</name>
		<weight>70</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>H</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="7">unique</tileset>
		<description>Dobhar-chu's are cryptids that resemble either an otter or a serpentine creature. It's generally described as having fur with some form of protective properties. Their colors can range from white to brown or black. Dobhar-chu's reside in lakes but have the capability of walking on land and running fast. Dobhar-chu's have been known not to hesitate in attacking creature, human or not, who trespass in their area. They weigh 70 stones and stand 30 to 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="46">
		<name>Doppelganger</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>p</symbol>
		<hitpoints>4</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="7" y="4"></tileset>
		<description>A doppelganger shapeshifts only into sentient beings and cannot communicate. It's said that doppelgangers are mirror images so that if their enemy is right handed they would effectively be left handed. Doppelgangers are incredibly rare and usually never noticed as they swiftly kill their prey and pretend to be them after death. Because of their inability to communicate they can't efficiently pretend to be their prey for too long and quickly move on to another prey. They assume whatever weight and height their prey inhibits.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="47">
		<name>Dullahan</name>
		<weight>40</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>u</symbol>
		<hitpoints>5</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="0">monster6</tileset>
		<description>A dullahan is a malevolent sprite without a head quite simply. They prefer to use whips during combat and are considered creatures as their intelligence is quite lacking. Naturally because dullahans resemble sprites they are generally 20 to 30 stones tall and 30 to 40 stones in weight.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="48">
		<name>Drake</name>
		<weight>400</weight>
		<height>180</height>
		<symbol>Đ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>19</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d10</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="3">dragon</tileset>
		<description>Drakes are offspring of degenerate dragons and are frail and thin, though faster then their ancestors. Drakes are rarely seen but around Wyrms by whom they receive protection. Wyrms protect them as if they were their own young. Drakes are seen only within the Plains of Endless Despair. Drakes often weigh between 200 and 400 stones with a wingspan of 180 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="49">
		<name>Drekavac</name>
		<weight>20</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>v</symbol>
		<hitpoints>7</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="3">undead</tileset>
		<description>Drekavac are creatures of the night and graveyard. It's said that they come from the souls of dead children. Some believe that Drekavacs can only be killed or laid to rest if their souls find peace. Drekavacs can change form from those of a bird, dog, fox, or a slender bodied baby with an out of proportion head. Features that remain constant for Drekavacs are it's height about 30 stones and it's horrifying screaming. For defense against the drekavac a dog must be obtained, for it's known that the drekavac are afraid of dogs. Drekavacs also hate the sunlight. They are generally 10 to 20 stones in weight.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="50">
		<name>Dromedary</name>
		<weight>300</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>ô</symbol>
		<hitpoints>1</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="12">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Dromedaries are extremely durable camels who never fall to fatigue. They are highly sought after by riders who fare the desert and barrens alike. Dromedaries are incredibly dependable and loving creatures but due to their lack of population it's incredibly rare to find a dromedary that isn't already domesticated. Dromedaries weigh 200 to 300 stones and stand 50 to 60 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="51">
		<name>Echeneis</name>
		<weight>15000</weight>
		<height>1100</height>
		<symbol>æ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="3">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Echeneis is a large legendary creature described in tall tales and yore that dates before the War of Souls. The stories tell of a fish 6 stones in length that is said to have latched onto ships, holding them back and slowing them down. The stories of Echeneis are told by ship captains in Dupree, Crecia, and other port cities. Echeneis would have weighed approximately 15000 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="52">
		<name>Faun</name>
		<weight>150</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>ü</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="12">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Fauns resemble satyrs except they fare well with other creatures, sentient and non-sentient alike. They attempt to win love of fair maidens. It's said if a Faun were to ever win the love of a maiden he would be transformed into a man, losing the legendary curse of the ill Satyr. Faun weigh 150 to 180 stones and stand 50 to 60 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="53">
		<name>Fei Lian</name>
		<weight>170</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>V</symbol>
		<hitpoints>10</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="4">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Fei lan have the body and legs of a stag and is are as swift as the wind. A long serpentine tail balances their heavy head as they resemble something of a sparrow with gleaming white bull horns and stripes. Fei Lian's elegant bodies are covered in golden fur and dark spots. These beasts are not carnivores, but would kill any creature that threatened them. Fei Lians weigh 150 to 170 stones and stand 30 to 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="54">
		<name>Fury</name>
		<weight>220</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>q</symbol>
		<hitpoints>13</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="4">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Furies are female cththonic deities of vengeance or supernatural personifications of the anger of the dead. They represent regeneration and the potency of creation, which both consumes and empowers. The perspective head of goddess Ettphemone is envisioned wreathed with serpents with the eyes dripping with blood. Sometimes they have the wings of a bat or bird and the body of a dog. Furies stand the height of a man from 50 to 60 stones tall and weigh 180 to 225 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="55">
		<name>Gashadokuro</name>
		<weight>250</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>J</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="6">undead</tileset>
		<description>Gashadokuro are giant skeletons many times taller than a human. It's thought that they are made of bones of people who have starved to death. After midnight the creatures walks streets making a ringing noise. Childrens stories say if you don't run away when the Gashadokuro approaches it will bite off their heads with it's giant teeth. Gashadokuro are actually quite agressive and weigh 225 to 250 stones, standing 70 to 80 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="56">
		<name>Grant</name>
		<weight>300</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>n</symbol>
		<hitpoints>4</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="12">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Grants are small horses that stand on their hind legs looking for possible danger. If they see danger they emit a piercing cry to warn other grants or those who have tamed the horse. They can only be found in very dense forests and are incredibly timid creatures. They weigh 250 to 300 stones and stand 40 to 50 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="57">
		<name>Gobriks</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>x</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="0">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Gobriks are 30 to 36 stones tall. Gobriks are incredibly grotesque creatures that almost inhibit qualities of phantoms. They originate from the bleak as degenerate offspring of inbreeding goblin slaves of the Dark Queen. The Dark Queen mocks the surface races and Gobriks are a result of her hatred of the so-called sky civilizations. Gobriks weigh around 30 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="58">
		<name>Golem</name>
		<weight>8000</weight>
		<height>120</height>
		<symbol>Ö</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d12</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="1">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Golems are elemental embodiments of their giant predecessors. It's said that golems were created accidentally by mages during the War of Souls. It's also said that if the Everspark were ever to be put back together, Golems would walk the surface again as their giants once had. Today Golems reside within the Bleak wander aimlessly without purpose.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="59">
		<name>Griffin</name>
		<weight>200</weight>
		<height>90</height>
		<symbol>î</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="9">monster2</tileset>
		<description>Griffins have the body of a lion with the wings and head of an eagle. Griffins represent royalty and are often seen on coat of arms of various households. Griffins are thought extinct, having happened during the War of Souls. They were half the size of the Roc weighing 250 stones with a wingspan of 90 to 220 stones..</description>
	</item>
	<item number="60">
		<name>Harpy</name>
		<weight>125</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>å</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="9">monster2</tileset>
		<description>Harpies are beautiful winged bird-women. They have protruding tongues and fangs and have the ability to bring life. They are also known as winged death-spirits best known for constantly stealing food. Harpies resemble woman at the height of 50 to 60 stones and 125 stones in weight.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="61">
		<name>Hercinia</name>
		<weight>8</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>X</symbol>
		<hitpoints>4</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="5">monster2</tileset>
		<description>Hercinias are birds with brightly glowing feathers. They are incredibly passive and feed only on insects, attacking only when provoked or when defending their young. Hercinias are the size of bald eagles which is 30 stones tall and 4 to 8 stones in weight.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="62">
		<name>Hydra</name>
		<weight>1500</weight>
		<height>180</height>
		<symbol>Q</symbol>
		<hitpoints>18</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="6" y="2">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Hydras are guardians within the Bleak. A Hydra generally has 9 heads with the mdidle head supposedly being immortal with poisonous venom and breath. It's very difficult to kill a hydra since cutting off a head only leads to two more growin back in it's place, at least that's the rumor. They stand 120 to 180 stones tall and weigh approximately 800 to 1500 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="63">
		<name>Incubus</name>
		<weight>175</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>û</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="1">monster7</tileset>
		<description>Incubai are lewd male creatures that take on the illusory appearance of a male human being and seeks sexual intercourse with women, usually while they're asleep. The incubai is believed to be a celestial creature who fell from the grace of Ettphemone because of his insatiable lust for women. Incubai like succubai innately shadowstep. An incubai weighs 175 stones and stand 60 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="64">
		<name>Ifrit</name>
		<weight>800</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>é</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d10</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="2">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Ifrits are elemental giants of fire. Ifrits are generally created by Archmages to protect portals, but there have been known to be a few Myrmidons to have been capable of summoning these horrifying beasts within the battlefield. Ifrits weigh 800 stones and stand 80 to 100 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="65">
		<name>Imp</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>ì</symbol>
		<hitpoints>2</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="10">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Imps are 10 stones tall and resemble goblins except for their  thin bodies and addition of wings. Imps aren't generally able to use their wings other than to flutter or glide from high places to ground safely. Imps weigh most generally between 30 to 50 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="66">
		<name>Kampe</name>
		<weight>500</weight>
		<height>120</height>
		<symbol>à</symbol>
		<hitpoints>13</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="4">unique</tileset>
		<description>Kampes are monstrous centaurine creatures who are have woman with serpentine hair and below the waist they have the scaly dragon features with a thousand vipers for feet. Sprouting from a Kampes waist are said to be the heads of fifty fearsom beasts such as lions, boars, and other wild animals. Kampes also have dark wings and a raised scorpions tail. Kampe were said to be guardians of the cyclops that worked their way into the underground caverns of the Bleak, thus Kampes may be found within the bleak - though now mostly guarding treasures and lost lore. Kampe weigh 500 to 800 stones and stand 120 to 130 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="67">
		<name>Krakkan</name>
		<weight>15000</weight>
		<height>8000</height>
		<symbol>Å</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d20</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="2">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Krakkan are considered a myth by seafarers of ages old. The myth is that there is a being that greatly resembles a colossal octopus living within the deep waters east of Crecia. Krakkan would have span 1800 stones in height and weighed 15000 or more incomprehensible stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="68">
		<name>Leucrota</name>
		<weight>60</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>ä</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="7" y="1">monster7</tileset>
		<description>Leucrota are dog-like beasts with a mouths that stretch ear-to-ear and plenty long teeth to boot. These scary looking creatures are said to shadowstep miles at a time and stalk easily prey, waiting until it sleeps to quickly bit it's head off. It's mentioned in some stories that the Leucrota could fit easily a horses head in it's mouth, so it is that this is the favored way of the leucrota to dispatch it's pray, quickly chomping down and through their neck. Some say the Leucrota swallows the heads whole and doesn't eat the body whatsoever. Leucrota weigh 60 stones and stands 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="69">
		<name>Llamhigyn Y Dwr</name>
		<weight>120</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>Z</symbol>
		<hitpoints>7</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="1">monster7</tileset>
		<description>Llamhigyn Y Dwrs are creatures that dwell in ponds, swamps, and lakes. They are amphibious, having the limbless body of a frogg, a long lizard tail, and membrane wings resembling those of a bat. It uses it's wings to leap out of the water and glide forth and swims very much like a tadpole using it's lizard tail. Llamhigyn Y Dwrs are carnivorous, making it a pest among fisherman communities. It can cause trouble by snapping fishing lines, eating livestock, and sometimes even attacking humans when food is sparce. Llamhigyn Y Dwrs weigh approximately 120 stones and stand 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="70">
		<name>Manticore</name>
		<weight>350</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>â</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="8">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Manticores are creatures with a humans face, lions body, and the stinger of scorpion. Manticores are said to swallow men whole and digest them as if they were snakes, using their teeth only as weapons in case of defense. Manticores are agressive creatures that don't do well in groups and prefer to hunt alone, stalking their prey, by which generally consists of travelers. Manticores weigh 350 stones and stand 30 to 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="71">
		<name>Marid</name>
		<weight>500</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>Æ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="6">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Marids are powerful giant elementals of water conjured by strong Archmages or the occasional Myrmidon during battle. Marids tear through enemies quickly with their magical and physical attacks. Marids weigh 300 to 500 stones and stand 80 to 100 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="72">
		<name>Minotaur</name>
		<weight>180</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>ö</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="5">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Minotaurs are creatures with the lower half of a man and the top half of a bull. They have cannabilitic hunger for mainly small children, young women, and are immune to fear which makes them incredibly fearsome. Though they are fearsom creatures, they are also quite unintelligent. They stand the height of a man and weigh no more than 180 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="73">
		<name>Monocerus</name>
		<weight>60</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>ñ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>7</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="5">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Monocerus' are dog-like beasts with a long horns in their forehead, almost more than bucks than dogs. Monocerus, though another way to describe a unicorn, doesn't resemble the unicorn in any aspect, and feasts off of the dead as a scavenger. Their fur is quite similar to a heiyina, shaggy and unclean - much like their temperament. Monocerus' weigh 60 some stones and stand 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="74">
		<name>Muldjewangk</name>
		<weight>190</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>j</symbol>
		<hitpoints>4</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="6">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Muldjewangk are lake monsters only visible at night when they glow slightly. These creatures are enormous toads that remain most generally within water of the pond, swamp, or perhaps bog, lighting the area. Muldjewangk surprisingly though they glow, are in fact blind. These creatures sense heartbeats and are incredibly timid with the ability to swim and run incredibly fast. Obviously their only downfall is the inability to sense the undead, as thus they have been destroyed in most regions of the Mellowdeep Marsh. Muldjewangk weigh 190 stones and stand 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="75">
		<name>Muscaliet</name>
		<weight>5</weight>
		<height>3</height>
		<symbol>Ü</symbol>
		<hitpoints>1</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="11">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Muscaliets are creatures with the body of a hare, tail of a squirrel, and teeth of a boar. These creatures are incredibly timid and hide most times of the day within tufts of grass, eating only the grass and flowers that inhabit the eastern cost of Sedia. These creatures weigh no more than 5 stones and stand 2 to 3 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="76">
		<name>Myrmecoleon</name>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>è</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="0">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Myrmecoleons are huge ants that supposedly kills other ants and small animals. These ants are incredibly dangerous to any creature whatsoever in large swarms, and inhabit the Bleak. They weigh 2 stones each, standing 1 stone tall they generally live in swarms of a few thousand, up to as much as 10 to 20 thousand which if focused could easily destroy any city within Sedia.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="77">
		<name>Nymph</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>Ñ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>2</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="8" y="8">unique</tileset>
		<description>Nymphs are said to be natural entities of nature, spirits of the woods. They take the appearance of young, beautiful girls. They are not immortal however, though they are long-lived, and their lives end with the death of a particular natural object, such as a tree, to which they are attached. Nymphs personify the fertility and creative powers of nature. Nymphs are the size of a woman, with similar weight and distinguishable features. Nymphs are rare and may be found in mostly woodland areas.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="78">
		<name>Ogre</name>
		<weight>400</weight>
		<height>100</height>
		<symbol>ò</symbol>
		<hitpoints>5</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="6" y="4">unique</tileset>
		<description>Ogres are large giants whose mind was tainted by the evil of Dekkashraen. Ogres stand up to 100 stones tall and weigh 300 to 400 stones. Ogres use primitive weapons and live in destructive nuclear families.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="79">
		<name>Onocentaur</name>
		<weight>200</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>ë</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="8">unique</tileset>
		<description>Onocentaurs are creatures with the upper body of man and lower of an ass. Onocentaurs have violent tempers and do not endure in capture, ramming themselves into walls until they die. Onocentaurs weigh up to 200 stones and stand 30 to 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="80">
		<name>Parandrus</name>
		<weight>150</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>µ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="5">unique</tileset>
		<description>Parandrus are beasts that can conceal itself by changing their appearance to camoflauge themselves in their surrounding environment. They are said to be ox-sized, long-haired, with antlers and cloven hooves. These creatures weigh generally 150 stones and stand 30 to 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="81">
		<name>Pegasus</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>Φ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>18</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="8" y="4">unique</tileset>
		<description>Pegasus' are white winged horses that live in small herds in forest areas. There is very rarely just one pegasus in the same area. It's also very rare for a pegasus to befriend a human as humans are known to temper horses, something a pegasus is very well aware of due to their intelligence. Their height and weight quotients are directly comparable to that of a standard horse plus an 80 stone wingspan.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="82">
		<name>Perytons</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>Γ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="5">unique</tileset>
		<description>Perytons are herbivore stags with black antlers and horns, rows of sharp teeth, golden fur, and feathered wings and hindquarters. They may vary in different colors such as black, gray, brown, gold, white, and very rarely a blue, green, scarlet, red, or orange. They are considered to be vicious because of their wild behavior and seclusion from civilization, but it's possible to approach them with slow movement without causing hostility. Their weight and height are quite comparable to that of a standard buck or doe.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="83">
		<name>Phoenix</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>É</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="8" y="5">unique</tileset>
		<description>Phoenix's are sacred firebirds found in colder climates as their internal fire makes them too hot to live in any other climate. They have both red and gold plumage. It's said that at the end of their life-cycle, which is about 500 years, the phoenix builds itself a nest of cinnamon twigs that it then ignites; both nest and bird burn fiercely and are reduced to ashes, by which a new, young phoenix arises. The phoenix is a bird of prey commonly diving into the cold waters of the arctic to get their food which consists mostly of fish, krill, baby mammals, and eaven ears of adult bears. A phoenix typically weighs 80 stones and stands 30 to 40 stones tall with an immense wingspan.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="84">
		<name>Quanlier</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>Ω</symbol>
		<hitpoints>2</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="9" y="2">unique</tileset>
		<description>Quanliers are creatures with the head of a wolf, the torso of a man, the arms of a dog, and the legs of a jackal. It feeds on human flesh and most small animals. It's said that they can run incredibly fast, so much so that they can trek leagues in seconds. A quanliers weight and height resembles that of a standard wolf.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="85">
		<name>Roc</name>
		<weight>500</weight>
		<height>240</height>
		<symbol>π</symbol>
		<hitpoints>10</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="4">dragon</tileset>
		<description>A large bird of prey, about twice the size of a bald eagle, is often depicted as white and is reputed to have been able to carry off and eat elephants. It's a very rare bird that might very well be extinct. Rocs are 500 stones and stand 180 to 240 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="86">
		<name>Satyr</name>
		<weight>60</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>Σ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="3" y="5">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Satyrs are a troop of male companions who have a human torso, goat legs, a goat tail, pointed ears, horns, curly hair, and full beards. Described as roguish but faint-hearted folk they are also quite subversive and dangerous. They are lovers of wine and women by which they steal from caravans or small towns to do unspeakable things to as slaves. Satyrs weigh 60 stones and stand 40 to 55 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="87">
		<name>Scarab</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>10</height>
		<symbol>∞</symbol>
		<hitpoints>1</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="7" y="2">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Scarabs are very large beetles that burrow within the flesh of large or colossal creatures, much like a parasite. These creatures could be compared easily to ticks. Scarabs weigh 20 to 30 stones and stand 10 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="88">
		<name>Sceadugenga</name>
		<weight>150</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>ε</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="4">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Sceadugenga are said to neither be alive or dead and can shapeshift, which is generally incorrect as they are clearly alive and merely shadowwalk constantly. Sceadugenga resemble panthers and humans alike, or perhaps humans with panther features. They certainly have tails by which they use for balance when running fast. Sceadugenga weigh 150 stones and stand 50 to 60 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="89">
		<name>Schilla</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>δ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>10</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="9">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Schilla are spiders with a human head that communicates telepathically. They creatures are found all throughout the Bleak, and many ruins. These creatures are said to have been the death of lizardling creatures as they inhabit most the same areas that those draconian creatures once had. It's not said why Schilla prefer these areas and it's rumored they have an ulterior motive regarding draconian magic. Schill can weigh from 30 stones to 800 stones depending on their size and likewise range from 10 stones to 100 stones in height.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="90">
		<name>Serpent</name>
		<weight>300</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>σ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>11</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="4">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Serpents are creatures with a snake body and human head. Serpents prefer to live in water and are rarely seen elsewhere, though they are able to move about on ground. They are not able to live within hot environments and prefer cold to cool temperatures. Serpents can weigh from 1 stone to 300 stones and range from 1 to 800 stones in length.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="91">
		<name>Shishi</name>
		<weight>180</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>τ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>13</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="6">monster4</tileset>
		<description>Shishi's are dogs with a lion-like mane and fur. Shishi are posted right and left of temple and house entrances as guardians against evil spirits. They can also be found on roofs but are often seen in pairs. The shishi throw their children off cliffs in order to test their strength. Despite this instance of callous disregard for their children's health, the parents are quite protective of their young. Shishi weigh 180 stones and stand 30 to 40 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="92">
		<name>Siren</name>
		<weight>150</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>Θ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="1">monster1</tileset>
		<description>Sirens are serpent-like creatures who ensnare creatures with their lulling songs. They inhabit areas surrounded by water. Sirens are incredibly dangerous and prey on traveling sailors. Sirens weigh most generally 150 stones and stand 50 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="93">
		<name>Succubus</name>
		<weight>125</weight>
		<height>55</height>
		<symbol>φ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="1">monster1</tileset>
		<description>Succubai are beautiful and desirable women, unlike their male counterparts, Incubai. Though they sometimes have bat-like wings or other scary feaures like horns, tails, hooves, or fangs - they represent lust. Succubi appear to men in the night and seduce them into sexual encounters so they can bear children. Celibate monks seemed to be especially prone to such attacks, often blaming Succubai for their lustful thoughts or sexual dreams. Succubai could suck the life force of men, leaving them exhausted or even killing them. Seccubai innately shadowstep. Succubai weigh 125 to 130 stones and stand 55 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="94">
		<name>Svagin</name>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>ß</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="7">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Svagin are large swarms of bloodsucking insects. Svagin can range incredibly in size from 3 stones diameter to leagues of what might be considered a plague. Svagin are incredibly dangerous.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="95">
		<name>Tarasque</name>
		<weight>400</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>α</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="7" y="5">dragon</tileset>
		<description>Tarasques are menacing beasts that cause much devastation to landscape. The tarasque is a sort of dragon with six short legs like a bear's, an ox-like body covered with a turtle shell, and a scaly tail that ended in a scorpions stinger and lion's head. Tarasques weigh 400 stones and stand 80 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="96">
		<name>Thunderbird</name>
		<weight>3000</weight>
		<height>330</height>
		<symbol>ê</symbol>
		<hitpoints>14</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="5">dragon</tileset>
		<description>Thunderbirds are supernatural birds that beat their enormous wings causing thunder and stirring the wind. They're said to be the bringers of rain and storms, large enough to hunt small whales individually. They are the predecessors of Rocs and are though extinct. Thunderbirds would have weighed 3000 stones and with a wingspan of 330 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="97">
		<name>Tikbalang</name>
		<weight>220</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>£</symbol>
		<hitpoints>8</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="2">dragon</tileset>
		<description>Tikbalangs are creatures that have a horse's head, body of a human, but with the feet of a horse. They travel at night and rape female sentient beings. The raped women will then give birth to more Tikbalang. They are also believed to cause travelers to lose their way particularly in mountains or forest areas. Tikbalang are very playful with people, and they usually make a person imagine things that aren't real. Sometimes a tikbalang will drive a person crazy. Legends say that when rain falls while teh sun in shining, a pair of tikbalangs are being wed. Tikbalangs stand 60 stones tall and weigh approximately 220 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="98">
		<name>Tikoloshe</name>
		<weight>240</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>ś</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="0" y="1">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Tikoloshe are bear-like humanoids considered to be mischievous spirits as they can become invisible at will by swallowing pebbles. It's head is like that of a teddy-bear, but it has a thick, sharp, boney ridge on top of it's head. Tokoloshes have a hole in their head. They're immensely strong. The ridge on their head goes from above the Tikoloshe's forehead to the back of the head, and with this ridge it can knock down an ox by running and butting it. Tikoloshes are 60 stones tall and weigh 240 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="99">
		<name>Tiyanak</name>
		<weight>30</weight>
		<height>12</height>
		<symbol>њ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d8</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="9">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Tiyanaks resemble small children except the horns and sharp teeth on their face. They are offpsring between incubai and creatures that are not mankind. Incubai rarely favor sentient beings other than humans, and the result of the rare few are Tiyanaks. Tiyanaks grow quickly within the womb and during the third trimester bore a hole through their mother, killing her. The Tiyanak lives within the dead body of the mother eating her insides for a month before it leaves the body and finds another human by which it can bore itself into. Tiyanaks weigh 30 stones and stand no more than 10 to 12 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="100">
		<name>Tlatecuhtli</name>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<height>1</height>
		<symbol>љ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="1">monster7</tileset>
		<description>Tlatecuhtli are huge frogs that are strongly used as examples of mage spire teachers for the representation of life, death, and rebirth. The Tlatecuhtli after it dies floats in the air suspended for a few minutes before it falls back to the ground renewed as a new creature. Tlatecuhtli are incredibly timid. They weigh 1 stone and stand 1 stone tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="101">
		<name>Unicorn</name>
		<weight>400</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>ù</symbol>
		<hitpoints>10</hitpoints> 
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="12">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Unicorns are beautiful large horses with spiral horns growing out of their forehead. The horn and the unicorns blood are used in medicine due to their healing properties. The horn is also known as teh "Bane of Evil" in that it has the ability to dispel anything malignant in water and can also kill most truely evil creatures it comes in contact with. Unicorns stand 50 stones tall and weigh 400 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="102">
		<name>Undines</name>
		<weight>160</weight>
		<height>60</height>
		<symbol>ч</symbol>
		<hitpoints>15</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="0">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Undines are sea faries who appear as seahorses with human faces. It's said that undines lack souls which constitutes for the forelorn looks and intense passiveness. They weigh 160 stones and span 60 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="103">
		<name>Wendigo</name>
		<weight>150</weight>
		<height>50</height>
		<symbol>э</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="2" y="5">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Wendigos are considered cannabilistic spirits having some similar characteristics between a zombie and a being that lives on blood. It's believed that humans can change into wendigos when they indulge in cannabalism. In some cases, possession causes the transformation, while some say that being bitten by a Wendigo can also cause it. Whil hunting, the wendigo follows its prey, always just out of sight, until it gets a chance to pounce. As for appearnace it is quite often describe as a tall thin humanoid creature, sometimes said to be twisted, bloodstained or fanged. Wendigos weigh 150 to 200 stones and stand 50 to 60 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="104">
		<name>Will'o'Wisp</name>
		<weight>60</weight>
		<height>6</height>
		<symbol>ж</symbol>
		<hitpoints>6</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="10">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Will'o'Wisps are also known as fairy lights, they're a debatable phenomenon. Humans who follow them can be lead to a fairy gather it's said, or even to a fairy realm if they manage to do so without getting lost; as the strange lights have a tendency to flicker and fade in and out of sight. Will'o'Wisps exists, though fairies do not, and are in fact quite mischievous creatures that inhibit many magical properties, probably a side affect of the War of Souls. Will'o'Wisps weigh nothing, but are seemingly ethereal and can only be touched by magic. They span from 6 stones to 60 stones in width.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="105">
		<name>Wyvern</name>
		<weight>300000</weight>
		<height>30000</height>
		<symbol>Ď</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d20</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="6">dragon</tileset>
		<description>Wyverns are colossal, ancient, dragons who have aged so much they lost theirs wings and tails have enlarged. They look more-or-less like Worms, incredibly large ones at that. They sometimes burrow within the ground as the Plains of Endless Despair can be quite ridden with magical properties that are incredibly dangerous. They protect the drakes that sour about the area of the Plains of Endles Despair as if they were their own children. Wyverns can talk telepathically.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="106">
		<name>Xolotl</name>
		<weight>80</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>ш</symbol>
		<hitpoints>4</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="0">dragon</tileset>
		<description>Xolotl are horrible underworld dogs whose legs and feet are backwards. It's ears can swivel in any direction. Every evening it's said that xolotls travel secret passageways up to the surface to catch and drag down its prey and feast in packs upon the flesh of an innocent lone traveler. Xolotls weigh 50 to 80 stones and stand 30 stones tall.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="107">
		<name>Yale</name>
		<weight>250</weight>
		<height>30</height>
		<symbol>д</symbol>
		<hitpoints>3</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d4</damage>
		<tileset x="5" y="11">monster3</tileset>
		<description>Yales are beasts with flexible horns that they can move at will. They resemble most generally bucks, or deer as it were. Yale are passive magical creatures that prefer to be left alone. They stand 30 to 40 stones tall and weigh 150 to 250 stones.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="108">
		<name>Yara-ma-yha-who</name>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<height>2</height>
		<symbol>й</symbol>
		<hitpoints>2</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d2</damage>
		<tileset x="1" y="5">monster5</tileset>
		<description>Yara-ma-yha-who are little red men who have large teethless heads and suckers for hands and feet. They stand no more than 2 stones tall and weigh 1 to 2 stones. They are thieves and hunger for blood - or more particularly blood of magical creatures. They are found most generally wherever you can find other magical creatures.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="109">
		<name>Yeti</name>
		<weight>300</weight>
		<height>80</height>
		<symbol>đ</symbol>
		<hitpoints>16</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d6</damage>
		<tileset x="4" y="10">monster6</tileset>
		<description>Yetis are ape-like beasts that reside in the cold mountainous regions of the Northern Reach. These creatures are mostly passive creatures though they will eat anything and everything when they are starved, including humans and other Yetis. They stand 80 stones tall and can weigh from 300 to 500 stones depending on when they last ate.</description>
	</item>
	<item number="110">
		<name>Ziz</name>
		<weight>1300</weight>
		<height>40</height>
		<symbol>ś</symbol>
		<hitpoints>20</hitpoints>
		<damage>1d10</damage>
		<tileset x="8" y="3">unique</tileset>
		<description>Ziz are enormous griffin-like bird creatures. They can have a wingspan so wide it blocks out the sun from miles above, though they themselves aren't so big.  Ziz are good hearted creatures who where used to protect livestock in ages old from other creatures. Ziz are now extinct since the War of Souls but stood 40 stones tall and weighed 1300 stones.</description>
	</item>
</itemlist>
