<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="Environments.xsl"?>
<!-- <title>Races List</title>
	 Race list was created in XML on 11/29/12
	 The list was extended for implementation in Exploring The Bleak : Online
	 on 11-29-2012. The list is used in Plains of Sedia : Origins, Developed by
	 Nathaniel Inman of The Other Experiment Studio found @ www.theoestudio.com
	 All contents within are licensed under GPLv3 -->
<racelist name="Races List">
	<race number="01">
		<name>Kobold</name>
		<tileset x="4" y="10">monster3</tileset>
		<naturalac>20</naturalac>
		<height>3-5</height>
		<weight>60-120</weight>
		<stats str="8" dex="8" int="10" wis="14" con="8" cha="13" luc="9"></stats>
		<haircolor>Bald,Black,Gray,White</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Golden,Green,White,Black</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Green,White,Black</skincolor>
		<description>Kobolds are similar to goblins except slightly thinner of build. They are almost reptilian in appearance and are said to be descendants of the original draconians. Kobolds are found predominately within Narsis or in clusters of clans within the Bleak.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="02">
		<name>Dwarf</name>
		<tileset x="4" y="1">monster6</tileset>
		<naturalac>15</naturalac>
		<height>3-5</height>
		<weight>120-230</weight>
		<stats str="12" dex="8" int="9" wis="11" con="12" cha="9" luc="9"></stats>
		<haircolor>Black,Brown,Red</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Brown,Golden,Black,Gray</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Dark,Black</skincolor>
		<description>Dwarves are short and stout demihumans. They spend most of their time in mines or forges working hard to provide for their families. Their primary home is within the province of Jewall but occasionally venture to other cities for trade, especially Tharsis.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="03">
		<name>Gnome</name>
		<tileset x="1" y="2">monster6</tileset>
		<naturalac>12</naturalac>
		<height>2-4</height>
		<weight>60-170</weight>
		<stats str="11" dex="9" int="11" wis="9" con="10" cha="9" luc="11"></stats>
		<haircolor>Brown,Blonde</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Black,Brown,Gray</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Tan,Dark</skincolor>
		<description>Gnomes used to be slaves of the Dwarfs and still hold immense animosity towards their sister race. Gnomes are otherwise very docile and tend to lean towards religious lives of servitude to this day within aristocratic manors.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="04">
		<name>Elf</name>
		<tileset x="6" y="2">classm</tileset>
		<naturalac>8</naturalac>
		<height>4-5</height>
		<weight>70-130</weight>
		<stats str="9" dex="12" int="11" wis="11" con="9" cha="9" luc="8"></stats>
		<haircolor>Brown,Blonde,Green,Blue</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Golden,Blue,Green</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>White,Tan</skincolor>
		<description>Elves are thin and medium height creatures who live primarily within the trees south of Tharsis called Darkwood forest. Elves are secretive beings who clan together and rarely venture outside of woodland.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="05">
		<name>Half-elf</name>
		<tileset x="6" y="3">classm</tileset>
		<naturalac>9</naturalac>
		<height>4-5</height>
		<weight>90-140</weight>
		<stats str="10" dex="12" int="10" wis="10" con="9" cha="10" luc="9"></stats>
		<haircolor>Brown,Blonde,Green,Red</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Brown,Golden,Blue,Green</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>White,Tan,Dark</skincolor>
		<description>Half-elfs are half elf and half human. Half-elfs have a tendency to lean towards their human side when rebellious by growing out facial hair, something their elvish brothers cannot reproduce. Half-elfs are rare in society as elves stand within their forest, rarely venturing out.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="06">
		<name>Halfling</name>
		<tileset x="6" y="5">classm</tileset>
		<naturalac>11</naturalac>
		<height>2-3</height>
		<weight>60-120</weight>
		<stats str="9" dex="11" int="10" wis="10" con="9" cha="10" luc="11"></stats>
		<haircolor>Black,Brown,Blonde</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Brown,Black,Green</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>White</skincolor>
		<description>Halflings are half the height of a normal human. Halflings favor thievary within large cities, but Lord Mandak is living proof that their hearts are much larger than their size. Halflings are very well-rounded and lucky beings who are successful and most things they set their attention on.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="07">
		<name>Goblin</name>
		<tileset x="5" y="1">monster1</tileset>
		<naturalac>13</naturalac>
		<height>2-3</height>
		<weight>70-80</weight>
		<stats str="8" dex="8" int="12" wis="9" con="12" cha="12" luc="9"></stats>
		<haircolor>Black,Brown</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Red,Brown,Green</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Green,Dark,Black</skincolor>
		<description>Goblins are incredibly mischievous and tricky beings. Because of their high intelligence they tend to work quite successfully in banks and at general commerce. Goblins are in all parts of society and are rarely seen outside of large cities.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="08">
		<name>Troll</name>
		<tileset x="0" y="14">monster1</tileset>
		<naturalac>14</naturalac>
		<height>5-8</height>
		<weight>280-420</weight>
		<stats str="11" dex="12" int="11" wis="9" con="11" cha="8" luc="8"></stats>
		<haircolor>Brown,Blonde,White</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Blue,Hazel,Gray</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Gray,Dark</skincolor>
		<description>Trolls are reclusive creatures who occassionally work as sentries in large cities if they're social enough. Most of the time trolls stay within small families within the woods outside of cities, just close enough to trade for essential items.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="09">
		<name>Orc</name>
		<tileset x="3" y="10">classm</tileset>
		<naturalac>15</naturalac>
		<height>5-6</height>
		<weight>160-280</weight>
		<stats str="12" dex="8" int="11" wis="8" con="12" cha="9" luc="10"></stats>
		<haircolor>Black,Brown</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Red,Brown,Black</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Dark,Red</skincolor>
		<description>Orcs are warbringers. They reside in the fireforge chasm and wage war on their neighbor dwarves. Ironholde prison holds their captives where they force their captives to mine rare minerals for secret trade throughout the continent of sedia. Orcs occasional raid cities, causing the occasional half-orc to sprout up. Orcs will kill half-orcs on sight, so the bastard children are usually brought up by their mothers or killed for humans hatred of the orcs.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="10">
		<name>Half-orc</name>
		<tileset x="1" y="2">monster1</tileset>
		<naturalac>12</naturalac>
		<height>5-6</height>
		<weight>150-250</weight>
		<stats str="12" dex="9" int="10" wis="8" con="12" cha="9" luc="10"></stats>
		<haircolor>Black,Brown,Blonde,Red</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Red,Brown,Black,Green</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Dark,Black,Red</skincolor>
		<description>Half-orcs are the children of orcs who raid cities. Half-orcs are killed by their orc brood if seen, and are rarely brought up in a secure home with two parents as even their mothers tend to drown these bastard young after birth. Half-orcs are a hated half race who lean towards battle or drink to repress their troublesome lives.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="11">
		<name>Quickling</name>
		<tileset x="2" y="10">monster2</tileset>
		<naturalac>7</naturalac>
		<height>2-3</height>
		<weight>20-50</weight>
		<stats str="8" dex="14" int="8" wis="8" con="9" cha="12" luc="11"></stats>
		<haircolor>Bald</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Blue,Hazel,Gray,Green</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>White,Tan,Gray</skincolor>
		<description>Quicklings are incredibly fast creatures who resemble slightly their halfling brother breed. Quicklings when excited occassionally talk to fast, sounding like buzzing bees or squeals. They talk quickling in this way to their own race for secretive communication. This race is incredibly tricky and quarelsome in society as they greatly favor thievary.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="12">
		<name>Pixie</name>
		<tileset x="2" y="9">monster2</tileset>
		<naturalac>5</naturalac>
		<height>1-2</height>
		<weight>8-15</weight>
		<stats str="8" dex="12" int="11" wis="12" con="8" cha="11" luc="8"></stats>
		<haircolor>Pink,Green,Purple,Blue</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Green,Blue,Purple</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>White,Gray</skincolor>
		<description>Pixies are the female species that are born by Lythantos into the Shanto Woodlands. These creatures occasionally mate with sprites, and leave their young after birth to grow either with their sprite brothers or pixie sisters after maturation. The species is strange and magical.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="13">
		<name>Sprite</name>
		<tileset x="1" y="9">monster2</tileset>
		<naturalac>5</naturalac>
		<height>1-2</height>
		<weight>9-20</weight>
		<stats str="8" dex="12" int="12" wis="11" con="9" cha="10" luc="8"></stats>
		<haircolor>Red,Blue,Black,White</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Red,Golden,Gray</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Gray,Black</skincolor>
		<description>Sprite males seperate from their pixie sisters unless it's time to mate. Sprites favor more war-natured society than the pixies, and occasionally will fight over a mate during the Burning Oeva, killing aggressors so that only the strongest sprite will reproduce. Pixies will give birth to many young at once, causing the population to decrease during mating season but boom 5 months after when the young are born.</description>
	</race>
	<race number="14">
		<name>Human</name>
		<tileset x="0" y="0">monster1</tileset>
		<naturalac>10</naturalac>
		<height>4-6</height>
		<weight>120-240</weight>
		<stats str="10" dex="10" int="10" wis="10" con="10" cha="10" luc="10"></stats>
		<haircolor>Black,Brown,Blonde,Red</haircolor>
		<eyecolor>Brown,Blue,Green,Hazel</eyecolor>
		<skincolor>Black,Brown,Blonde,Red</skincolor>
		<description>Humans are the most common and well-rounded race. Humans are a new race, but because of their quick reproduction they are beginning to take over the continent of Sedia. Humans are now the backbone of society and are said to have been made in a smaller mirror image of Lythantos' Ancients, the lords of the Old World.</description>
	</race>
</racelist>
